Taylor Basinger

🕈 Mountain Home, AR, US 🗷 Taylor@TaylorBasinger.com 🛘 8704054734 🛅 https://www.linkedin.com/in/taylor-basinger/

SUMMARY

Full-Stack developer with 3+ years of work experience, skilled in React.js, Typescript, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Python, Node.js, SQL. I have 10+ years diverse IT career background from Systems Engineering, Networking, to Software Developing. I am experienced doing full stack development, from creating SQL databases, building the APIs, to designing web app. Strong problem-solving abilities, with a passion for technology and a track record of delivering customer-centric solutions.

EXPERIENCE

Programmer Analyst

Baxter International Inc

April 2022 - Present, Mountain Home, AR

- · Developed and deployed full-stack web applications using React, Node.js, and JavaScript, resulting in a 20% increase in user engagement.
- · Analyzed, coded, and recommended solutions to stakeholders, optimizing platform utilization.
- · Led development and deployment of complex technical objects globally.
- · Communicated project technical issues and provided future-proof solutions.
- Evaluated application performance for efficiency and effectiveness. Built various web applications and increased performance by 50%, improved user experience through testing and optimization, and reduced bottlenecks and deployment times down to 5 minutes.
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$ Developed web applications in accordance with customer requirements.

IT Analyst

Baxter International Inc

July 2019 - April 2022, Mountain Home, AR

- · Developed and maintained websites using open-source technology, including JavaScript, HTML, and CSS.
- · Managed and completed projects from start to finish in collaboration with cross-functional teams.
- · Upgraded and maintained Windows server environment and scripted automation tasks using PowerShell and Python.
- · Configured and maintained MS SQL databases.
- · Supported JDE environment and developed C# applications.
- Installed and maintained PC and server hardware, network devices, and software.
- · Decreased response time for high priority tasks by 75%, reduced downtime by 50%, and increased system availability by 90%.

Assistant Technology Coordinator

Flippin School District

November 2016 - July 2019, Flippin, AR

- $\cdot \ Managed\ network\ systems\ and\ work station\ configuration,\ ensuring\ server\ performance,\ resiliency,\ and\ disaster\ recovery.$
- $\cdot \text{Supervised}$ the design, acquisition, and installation of equipment and systems.
- \cdot Educated instructional staff on technology integration in the classroom.
- \cdot Maintained Active Directory, Azure AD, and Google Suite.
- · Achieved a 96% uptime rate, reduced system backup time by 75%, and offered exceptional user experience with a satisfaction rate of 95%.

Computer Technician

Brooks Jeffrey

December 2015 - November 2016, Mountain Home, AR

- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$ Troubleshot and repaired PCs, servers, and networks.
- · Maintained Windows servers for multiple companies.
- \cdot Built, configured, and maintained networks, VPN access, and network security.
- Diagnosed and resolved network and system issues with an average resolution time of 2.5 hours, configured and managed Windows servers with success rate of 98%, installed virus protection software resulting in a 86% decrease in malware infection rate.

IT Specialist

Magness Oil Company

April 2014 - December 2014, Gassville, AR

- · Maintained network, servers, computers, phone system, POS systems, printers, and accessories.
- · Trained users on new software and equipment.
- · Implemented network solutions to improve system reliability, stability and performance, reducing responsive support incidents by 83%.

EDUCATION

(AAS), Information Technology - Networking Specialist

Arkansas State University · 2014

SKILLS

React, Node.js, TypeScript, Python, MS SQL, Git, HTML, CSS